Now there are a few disadvantages to impromptu speaking.
The first one that you need to be aware of is that your audience could get bored, alright?
And a lot of this has to do with structure, which I'm going to talk about in a minute, but you're thinking on your feet.
You know the topic, but you have to, while you're speaking impromptu with no preparation, you have to keep your audience interested.
You can't ramble on, you can't have random organizational patterns, you have to keep the audience with you.
So that's something that you run the risk of is your audience not staying with you.
Obviously your goal, your aim is to appear effective as a public speaker giving a well, thought-out speech.
Well, you're at a disadvantage if you're giving an impromptu speech because you're not giving a well thought-out speech, you just met the topic.
So you have to try and present a well thought-out speech, but you have to be careful because you have had no preparation time.
You also, one of the negatives is that you can't really put a lot of attention on details -you haven't had time to research, you haven't had time to come up with the finesse and the finite things about your speech, so you're going to miss out on some of those details.
And those are some of the negatives that are not such great things about impromptu speaking, so just be aware of that when you're having to give an impromptu speech.
Know that those are some of the pitfalls so that you might avoid them.